[ Computer beeping ]
LEADER : Bio-readouts are in the green .
Looks like she ´ s alive .
There goes our salvage , guys .
MED-TECH : How are we today ?
RIPLEY : Oh . Terrible .
MED-TECH : Better than yesterday , at least .
Where am I ?
MED-TECH : You ´ re safe .
You ´ re at Gateway Station . Been here a couple of days .
You were pretty groggy at first , but now you ´ re OK .
Looks like you ´ ve got a visitor .
Jonesy ! Come here !
Hey , come here .
How are you , you stupid cat ?
How are you ?
Where have you been ?
BURKE : Guess you two have met , huh ?
I ´ m Carter Burke . I work for the Company .
Don ´ t let that fool you . I ´ m really an OK guy .
I ´ m glad you ´ re feeling better .
They tell me the weakness and disorientation should pass soon .
That ´ s just natural side effects ...
of such an unusually long hypersleep .
What do you mean ?
How long was I out there ?
Has no one discussed this with you ?
No .
But , I mean , I don ´ t recognize this place .
No , I know . Uh ... OK .
This might be a shock . It ´ s long- -
How long ?
Please .
Fifty-seven years .
What ?
BURKE : You were out there for fifty-seven years .
You drifted right through the core systems .
It ´ s really just blind luck ...
that a deep-salvage team found you .
It ´ s one in a thousand , really .
You ´ re damn lucky to be alive , kiddo .
You could be floating out there forever .
You OK ?
[ Hiss ]
Oh .
[ Heartbeat ]
- [ Hiss ] - Oh !
BURKE : You OK ?
[ Hiss ]
Oh !
God !
BURKE : Nurse ! Please !
Someone get in here now !
RIPLEY : No !
BURKE : Now !
- Hold-- - Please .
DOCTOR : Hold her .
Kill me !
No !
MED-TECH : Bad dreams again ?
You want something to help you sleep ?
No .
I ´ ve slept enough .
Jonesy .
Come here .
[ Meow ]
Shh .
It ´ s all right .
It ´ s all right now .
It ´ s over .
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Chirping stops ]
BURKE : Hi . Sorry I ´ m late . Been running behind all morning .
RIPLEY : ls there any word about my daughter ?
Uh ... I think we should worry about the hearing now .
We don ´ t have a lot of time .
I read your deposition , and it ´ s great .
If you stick to that , we ´ ll be fine .
The thing is , there are gonna be a lot of heavyweights in there .
Feds , lnterstellar Commerce Commission ...
Colonial Administration , insurance company guys .
Do you have any news about my daughter ?
We did come up with some information .
Why don ´ t we sit down ?
I was hoping to wait until after the inquest .
Uh ...
" Amanda Ripley McClaren- - "
married name , I guess- -
" age sixty-six . "
That was at the time of her death ...
which was two years ago .
I ´ m real sorry .
Amy .
BURKE : She was cremated and interred ...
at Westlake Repository , Little Chute , Wisconsin .
No children . I checked .
I promised her ...
that I would be home for her birthday .
Her eleventh birthday .
Ohh ...
INVESTIGATOR : I ´ d like to go back to this point ...
about the override destruct elements .
I don ´ t understand this .
We have been here three and a half hours .
How many different ways do you want the same story ?
VAN LEUWEN : Look at it from our perspective , please .
Please ?
You freely admit to detonating the engines of ...
and thereby destroying an M-Class star freighter ...
a rather expensive piece of hardware .
INVESTIGATOR : Forty-two million in adjusted dollars .
That ´ s minus payload , of course .
VAN LEUWEN : The lifeboat ´ s flight recorder ...
corroborates some elements of your account ...
in that , for reasons unknown ...
the Nostromo set down on LV-426 ...
an unsurveyed planet at that time ...
that it resumed its course ...
and was subsequently set for self-destruct by you ...
for reasons unknown .
Not for reasons unknown .
I told you .
We set down on Company orders to get this thing ...
which destroyed my crew and your expensive ship .
The analysis team ...
which went over the lifeboat centimeter by centimeter ...
found no physical evidence of the creature you describe .
Good ! That ´ s because I blew it out of the goddamn air lock .
Like I said .
INVESTIGATOR : Are there any species ...
like this hostile organism on LV-426 ?
ECA REP : No . It ´ s a rock . No indigenous life .
Did IQs just drop sharply while I was away ?
Ma ´ am , I already said it was not indigenous .
It was a derelict spacecraft . It was an alien ship .
It was not from there .
Do you get it ? We homed in on its beacon .
And found something never recorded once ...
in over three hundred surveyed worlds .
" A creature that gestates inside a living human host . "
These are your words .
" And has concentrated acid for blood . "
RIPLEY : That ´ s right .
Look . I can see where this is going ...
but I ´ m telling you that those things exist .
Thank you , Officer Ripley . That will be all .
Please ! You ´ re not listening .
Kane--the crew member ...
Kane , who went into that ship , said he saw thousands of eggs .
Thank you . That will be all .
God damn it , that ´ s not all !
If one of those things gets down here , that will be all !
And all this bullshit you think is important ...
you can kiss all that good-bye !
It is the finding of this court of inquiry ...
that Warrant Officer E. Ripley ...
N-O-C-one-four-four-seven-two ...
has acted with questionable judgment ...
and is unfit to hold an ICC license ...
as a commercial flight officer .
Said license is hereby suspended indefinitely .
No criminal charges ...
will be filed against you at this time ...
and you are released on your own recognizance ...
for a six-month period of psychometric probation ...
to include monthly review by an ICC psychiatric technician .
These proceedings are closed .
BURKE : That could have been better .
Look , I think--Ripley .
RIPLEY : Van Leuwen .
Why don ´ t you just check out LV-426 ?
VAN LEUWEN : Because I don ´ t have to .
People have been there for over twenty years ...
and they never complained about any hostile organism .
RIPLEY : What people ?
VAN LEUWEN : Terraformers .
Planet engineers .
They go in , set up atmosphere processors ...
to make the air breathable .
It takes decades .
It ´ s what we call a shake ´ n ´ bake colony .
How many are there ? How many colonists ?
I don ´ t know . Sixty , maybe seventy families .
Do you mind ?
Families .
Jesus .
[ Honk honk ]
AL : I ´ ll be down in maintenance .
- Al ? - What ?
- Hey , Al . - What ?
LYDECKER : Remember you sent some wildcatters ...
out in the middle of nowhere last week ...
out past the ilium Range ?
One ´ s on the horn , a mom-and-pop survey team .
He ´ s onto something , wants his claim honored .
AL : Why wouldn ´ t it be honored ?
LYDECKER : Because you sent them on Company orders maybe ?
AL : Christ . Some haunch in a cushy office on Earth says ...
" Go look at a grid reference . "
We look . They don ´ t say why , and I don ´ t ask ...
because it takes two weeks to get an answer out here .
The answer is always , " Don ´ t ask . "
LYDECKER : What do I tell this guy ?
AL : As far as I ´ m concerned , if he finds something , it ´ s his .
- Lydecker ? - What ?
LYDECKER : You kids know you ´ re not supposed to be here !
Get out !
TIMMY : You go in places we can ´ t fit .
NEWT : So ? That ´ s why I ´ m the best !
MOTHER : Knock it off .
If I catch you playing in the air ducts , I ´ ll tan your hides .
NEWT : Mom , all the kids play- -
FATHER : Wait . Have a look at this .
Folks , we have scored big this time .
What is it , Dad ?
I ´ m not sure .
Let ´ s see if we can ´ t get a closer look at this thing ...
maybe through that crack on the side .
MOTHER : Shouldn ´ t we call in ?
Let ´ s wait till we know what to call it in as .
That ´ s about as close as we can get .
Should we look inside ?
MOTHER : You kids stay inside . I mean it .
We ´ ll be right back .
- TIMMY : OK . - NEWT : Bye .
TIMMY : Huh ?
NEWT : Timmy , they ´ ve been gone a long time .
TIMMY : It ´ ll be OK . Dad knows what he ´ s doing .
MOTHER : Mayday ! Mayday !
This is Alpha Kilo Two-four - niner calling Control !
This is Alpha Kilo Two-four-niner !
NEWT : Aah !
Aah !
[ Meow meow ]
[ Doorbell beeps ]
BURKE : Hiya , Ripley .
This is Lieutenant Gorman of the Colonial Marine Corps- -
Ripley , we have to talk .
We ´ ve lost contact with the colony on LV-426 .
I don ´ t believe this .
You guys throw me to the wolves ...
and now you want me to go back there ?
Forget it . It ´ s not my problem .
- Can I finish ? - No .
There ´ s no way .
GORMAN : You wouldn ´ t be going in with the troops .
I can guarantee your safety .
BURKE : These Colonial Marines are very tough hombres .
They ´ re packing state-of-the-art firepower .
There ´ s nothing they can ´ t handle .
Lieutenant , am I right ?
We ´ ve been trained to deal with situations like this .
Then you don ´ t need me . I ´ m not a soldier .
BURKE : But we don ´ t know exactly what ´ s going on .
It may be a downed transmitter .
But if it ´ s not ...
I ´ d like you there as an advisor , and that ´ s all .
What ´ s your interest in all this ? Why are you going ?
The Corporation co-financed that colony ...
along with Colonial Administration .
We ´ re getting into a lot of terraforming now ...
and building better worlds- -
RIPLEY : Yeah . I saw the commercial .
I don ´ t have time for this . I ´ ve got to get to work .
Right . I heard you ´ re working the cargo docks .
That ´ s right .
Running loaders and forklifts .
Yeah . So ?
Nothing . I think it ´ s great that you ´ re keeping busy .
I know it ´ s the only thing you could get .
There ´ s nothing wrong with it .
What would you say if I told you ...
I could get you reinstated as a flight officer ?
The Company ´ s already agreed to pick up your contract .
If I go .
Yeah , if you go .
Come on . That ´ s a second chance , kiddo .
I think personally for you ...
it would be the best thing to go and face this thing .
Get back on the horse .
Spare me . I ´ ve had my psych evaluation .
I know . I ´ ve read it .
You wake up every night , soaked in sweat- -
I said no , and I mean it !
Now please leave .
I am not going back ...
and I would not be any good to you if I did .
OK .
Shh .
Would you do me a favor ? Just think about it .
GORMAN : Thanks for the coffee .
[ Meow ]
Aah !
Oh .
[ Beeping ]
Hello .
Ripley .
You OK ?
RIPLEY : Just tell me one thing , Burke .
You ´ re going out there to destroy them , right ?
Not to study .
Not to bring back .
But to wipe them out .
That ´ s the plan . You have my word on it .
All right , I ´ m in .
I think that- -
And you , you little shithead ...
you ´ re staying here .
[ Hinges squeak ]
[ Chain jingling ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Coughing ]
DRAKE : They ain ´ t paying ´ us enough for this , man .
DIETRICH : Not enough to have to wake up to your face , Drake .
What ? ls that a joke ?
DIETRICH : I wish it were .
DRAKE : Hey , Hicks . Man , you look just like I feel .
APONE : All right , sweethearts ...
what are you waiting for , breakfast in bed ?
Another glorious day in the Corps .
A day in the Marine Corps is like a day on the farm .
Every meal ´ s a banquet , every paycheck a fortune ...
every formation a parade .
I love the Corps !
HUDSON : Man , this floor is freezing !
APONE : Want me to fetch your slippers ?
Gee , would you , sir ? I ´ d like that .
Look into my eye .
Fall in , people !
Come on , let ´ s go .
FROST : I hate this job .
APONE : Crowe , Wierzbowski , on your feet .
FROST : I ´ m talking about breathing , not this frozen shit .
DIETRICH : Yeah , Top , how about it ?
APONE : First assembly ´ s in fifteen , people . Shag it .
VASQUEZ : Hey , mira . Who ´ s Snow White ?
FERRO : She ´ s supposed to be some kind of consultant .
Apparently , she saw an alien once .
HUDSON : Whoopee-fucking-do !
Hey , I ´ m impressed .
VASQUEZ : Qué bonita .
HUDSON : Hey , Vasquez .
Have you ever been mistaken for a man ?
No . Have you ?
DRAKE : Ha ha ! Oh , Vasquez .
You ´ re just too bad .
HUDSON : Hey , Top , what ´ s the op ?
APONE : A rescue mission . You ´ ll love it .
There ´ s some juicy colonists ´ daughters ...
we have to rescue from their virginity .
SPUNKMEYER : Dumbass colonists .
SPUNKMEYER : What ´ s this crap supposed to be ?
FROST : Cornbread , I think .
HICKS : It ´ s good for you , boy . Eat it .
FROST : I wouldn ´ t mind getting more of that Arcturian poontang .
Remember that time ?
SPUNKMEYER : Yeah , but the one you had was a male .
FROST : It doesn ´ t matter when it ´ s Arcturian .
HUDSON : Hey , Bishop , do the thing with the knife .
BISHOP : Oh , please .
HUDSON : Come on . All right !
APONE : I don ´ t want to see that .
HUDSON : All right !
What are you doing , man ?
Quit messing around , Drake .
Bishop . Hey , man .
- Do it . - Hey , not me , man !
DRAKE : Yeah , you . Don ´ t move .
Trust me .
Aah !
APONE : All right , knock it off .
Thank you .
[ Laughter ]
DRAKE : Enjoy your meal .
That wasn ´ t funny , man .
BISHOP : Lieutenant Gorman ? Mr. Burke ?
BURKE : Yeah , thanks .
Looks like the new lieutenant ´ s too good to eat with us grunts .
FROST : Boy ´ s definitely got a corncob up his ass .
BURKE : I thought you never missed , Bishop .
You never said anything about an android being on board .
It never occurred to me .
It ´ s common practice to have a synthetic on board .
I prefer the term " artificial person . "
Right .
Is there a problem ?
BURKE : I ´ m sorry . I don ´ t know why I didn ´ t even ...
Ripley ´ s last trip , the syn- -
the artificial person malfunctioned .
Malfunctioned ?
There were problems , and a few deaths were involved .
I ´ m shocked .
Was it an older model ?
Yeah . The Hyperdyne Systems 120-A-2 .
That explains it . The A-2s always were a bit twitchy .
That could never happen now with our behavioral inhibitors .
It is impossible for me to harm ...
or allow to be harmed a human being .
Sure you don ´ t want some ?
[ Crash ]
Just stay away from me . You got that straight ?
FROST : Guess she don ´ t like the cornbread , either .
APONE : Squad , ten-hut ! Officer on deck !
GORMAN : As you were .
APONE : Quickly , quickly .
Settle down .
All right , listen up !
GORMAN : Good morning , Marines .
I ´ m sorry we didn ´ t have time to brief you before we left- -
HUDSON : Sir !
What is it , Hicks ?
HUDSON : Hudson , sir .
He ´ s Hicks .
What ´ s the question ?
Is this gonna be a stand-up fight or another bug-hunt ?
All we know is there ´ s still no contact with the colony ...
and a xenomorph may be involved .
APONE : Excuse me , sir . A what ?
GORMAN : A xenomorph .
HICKS : It ´ s a bug-hunt .
What exactly are we dealing with ?
GORMAN : Ripley .
RIPLEY : I ´ ll tell you what I know .
We set down on LV-426 .
A crew member was brought back on board ...
with something attached to his face ...
some kind of parasite .
We tried to get it off . It wouldn ´ t come off .
Later , it seemed to come off by itself and die .
Kane seemed fine .
We were all having dinner .
It must have laid something inside his throat ...
some sort of embryo .
He started ... Um , he- -
VASQUEZ : Look , man , I only need to know one thing- -
where they are .
DRAKE : Vasquez , kick ass .
VASQUEZ : Anytime , anywhere .
HUDSON : Right . Somebody said " alien ... "
she thought they said " illegal alien " and signed up .
- Fuck you , man . - Anytime , anywhere .
RIPLEY : Are you finished ?
I hope you ´ re right . I really do .
GORMAN : Yeah , OK . Right . Thank you , Ripley .
We have Ripley ´ s report on disk . I suggest you study it .
RIPLEY : Because just one of those things ...
wiped out my crew in less than twenty-four hours .
If the colonists have found that ship ...
there ´ s no telling how many have been exposed .
Do you understand ?
GORMAN : Anyway , we have it on disk , so look at it .
Any questions ?
What is it , Private ?
How do I get out of this chickenshit outfit ?
You secure that shit , Hudson .
All right .
Now listen up .
I want this thing to go smooth and by the numbers .
I want DCS and tactical database assimilation by 0830 .
Ordnance loading , weapons strip ...
and drop-ship prep details will have seven hours .
Now move it , people !
You heard the man , and you know the drill .
Assholes and elbows !
Hudson , come here . Come here !
APONE : I don ´ t care if you are short , Hudson . Get it done .
HUDSON : You ´ ll get lip cancer smoking those .
APONE : I want this loading lock sealed . Now !
- How many more , Spunkmeyer ? - Last one .
Good . Take it away .
SPUNKMEYER : Clear behind .
APONE : Did you check number three ?
Hi . I feel like a fifth wheel . Is there anything I can do ?
I don ´ t know . Is there anything you can do ?
Well , I can drive that loader .
I have a Class Two rating .
Be my guest .
Where you want it ?
Bay twelve , please .
APONE : We ´ re a team , and there ´ s nothing to worry about .
We come here , and we gonna conquer ...
and we gonna take some . Is that understood ?
That ´ s what we gonna do . We are going to get some .
All right , people , on the ready-line !
- Are you lean ? - Yeah !
- Are you mean ? - Yeah !
- What are you ? ! - Lean , mean Marines !
APONE : Get on the ready-line ! Get some today !
Get on the ready-line !
Move it out !
Move it out , God damn it !
Get hot ! One , two , three ! Get out ! Get out ! Get out !
Move it out ! Move it out ! Move it out !
One , two , three , four ! One , two , three !
[ Grunts ]
Absolutely badasses !
Let ´ s pack ´ em in ! Get in there !
Move it !
HICKS : Let ´ s go , let ´ s go .
APONE : One , two , three , four , five , six !
I want combat seating . You know your places .
Get those weapons stowed . Let ´ s go .
Come on . Settle down , people .
Lock them in , Hudson .
HUDSON : Ready to get it on ? You know it !
GORMAN : OK , Bishop , let ´ s go .
Roger .
HUDSON : I ´ m ready , man .
Ready to get it on ! Go !
FERRO : Stand by . Cross-locking now .
Pre-launch auto-cycle engage .
Primary couplers released .
Hit the internals .
HUDSON : Oh , shit , man .
FERRO : Confirm cross-lock and drop stations secured .
GORMAN : Affirmative . All drop stations secured .
Stand by . Ten seconds .
Stand by to initiate release sequencer ...
on my mark .
HUDSON : We ´ re on an express elevator to hell .
Going down !
Two , one , mark .
Whoo-hoo !
FERRO : Switch to DCS ranging .
SPUNKMEYER : Two-four-oh , nominal to profile .
FERRO : We ´ re in the pipe , five by five .
SPUNKMEYER : We ´ re picking up some hull ionization .
FERRO : Got it . Rough air ahead . We ´ re in for some chop .
RIPLEY : How many drops is this for you , Lieutenant ?
Thirty-eight .
Simulated .
How many combat drops ?
Uh , two ...
including this one .
DRAKE : Shit .
HUDSON : Oh , man .
Range zero-one-four . Turning on final .
FROST : I got a bad feeling about this drop .
CROWE : You always say , " l got a bad feeling about this drop . "
FROST : When we get back without you , I ´ ll call your folks .
GORMAN : All right . Let ´ s see what we can see .
Everybody on-line .
Looking good .
Drake , check your camera .
There seems to be a malfunction .
That ´ s better .
Pan it around a bit . Good .
HUDSON : I ´ m ready . Check it out . I am the ultimate badass .
HUDSON : State of the badass art .
You do not wanna fuck with me .
Check it out .
Hey , Ripley , don ´ t worry .
Me and my squad of ultimate badasses will protect you .
HUDSON : Check it out .
Independently targeting particle-beam phalanx .
Whap !
Fry half a city with this puppy .
We got tactical smart missiles ...
phase-plasma pulse-rifles , RPGs .
We got sonic , electronic ballbreakers !
We got nukes .
We got knives , sharp sticks- -
APONE : Knock it off , Hudson !
All right , gear up .
Two minutes , people . Get hot .
Somebody wake up Hicks .
FERRO : Coming around for a seven-zero-niner .
SPUNKMEYER : Terminal guidance locked in .
FERRO : Where ´ s the damn beacon ?
Oh , I see it .
RIPLEY : That ´ s the atmosphere processor ?
BURKE : Yep , that ´ s it .
Remarkable piece of machinery .
Completely automated .
We manufacture those , by the way .
GORMAN : OK , Ferro .
Take us in low over the main colony complex .
Storm shutters are sealed .
There ´ s no visible activity .
All right . Hold at forty .
FERRO : Roger .
GORMAN : Give me a slow circle of the complex .
Structure seems intact .
They still have power .
GORMAN : OK , Ferro . Set down on the landing grid .
Immediate dust-off on my clear , then stay on station .
FERRO : Down and clear .
APONE : Ten seconds , people . Look sharp !
I want a nice , clean dispersal this time .
Let ´ s go ! Move it out !
Head ´ em out !
GORMAN : First squad up , on-line .
Hicks , get yours in a cordon , and watch the rear .
APONE : Vasquez , take point .
Let ´ s move !
Move up .
Hudson , run a bypass .
Second squad , move up .
Flanking positions .
Second squad , on-line .
APONE : You set ?
Second team , move inside . Hicks , take the upper level .
APONE : Sir , you copying this ?
Looks like hits from small-arms fire .
We got some explosives damages , probably seismic survey charges .
Are you reading this ?
Keep it tight , people .
GORMAN : Hicks , Hudson , use your motion trackers .
HICKS : Nothing .
Not a goddamn thing .
GORMAN : Quarter and search by twos .
HICKS : OK , Dietrich , Frost , you ´ re up .
[ Beeping ]
[ Motion tracker beeping ]
[ Beeping louder ]
HUDSON : It ´ s right in here .
- Now ! - Now !
HUDSON : Hyah !
VASQUEZ : Good one , Hudson .
HUDSON : Uh , sir , we have a negative situation here .
Uh , moving on , sir .
RIPLEY : Wait .
Wait , tell him to ...
Hicks , back up .
Pan right .
There .
HICKS : You seeing this all right ?
Looks melted .
Somebody must have bagged one of Ripley ´ s bad guys here .
BURKE : Acid for blood .
If you like that , you ´ re gonna love this .
HUDSON : Quit screwing around .
APONE : Second squad , what ´ s your status ?
HICKS : We just finished our sweep .
Nobody ´ s home .
APONE : Roger . Sir , this place is dead .
Whatever happened here , we missed it .
The area ´ s secured .
Let ´ s go check their computer .
- It ´ s not secure . - The area ´ s secured .
GORMAN : First team , head for Operations .
Hudson , get their CPU on-line .
HUDSON : Affirmative .
Hicks , meet me at the south lock .
We ´ re coming in .
HUDSON : He ´ s coming in .
I feel safer already .
VASQUEZ : Pendejo jerkoff .
HUDSON : Sir , we got the CPU on-line . No problem .
GORMAN : Good . Stand by in Operations .
OK , let ´ s go .
Are you all right ?
Yes .
DRAKE : Sir ...
they sealed off this wing at both ends , welded the doors ...
and blocked off the stairs with heavy equipment .
But it looks like the barricade didn ´ t hold .
- Any bodies ? - No , sir .
FROST : Last stand .
DRAKE : Must have been a hell of a fight .
HICKS : Looks that way .
GORMAN : All right , Drake , this way .
We should be able to cut through the med lab to Operations .
HICKS : Lieutenant .
Gorman .
Are those the same ones ?
Careful , Burke .
HICKS : Looks like love at first sight to me .
Oh , he likes you , Burke .
BISHOP : Two are alive . The rest are dead .
" Surgically removed before embryo implantation .
" Subject Marachuk , John J. , died during the procedure . "
They killed him taking it off .
[ Beeping ]
FROST : Yo , Hicks .
I think we got something here .
HICKS : Behind us .
RIPLEY : One of us ?
GORMAN : Apone , where are your people ?
Anybody in D-Block ?
APONE : Negative . We ´ re all in Operations .
DRAKE : Talk to me , Frosty .
FROST : Let ´ s keep moving , baby .
[ Crash ]
HICKS : It ´ s moving .
DRAKE : Which way ?
FROST : It ´ s coming straight for us .
Straight up .
[ Beeping louder ]
DRAKE : Fuck !
HICKS : Hold up .
Ripley .
RIPLEY : Hey , shh , it ´ s all right .
It ´ s all right .
GORMAN : Grab her , Corporal .
RIPLEY : Don ´ t be afraid . Come on . We won ´ t hurt you .
Shh . It ´ s all right . It ´ s OK .
Come on out . Come on . Easy .
HICKS : I got her . Ow ! Damn !
RIPLEY : Don ´ t let her go .
HICKS : She ´ s under the grill !
GORMAN : Frost , get your light up here .
RIPLEY : Where ´ d she go ?
FROST : She ´ s on the other side .
RIPLEY : Shine the light !
BISHOP : Here . Here .
RIPLEY : Keep back . Don ´ t scare her .
HICKS : Grab her . We ´ re gonna lose her .
RIPLEY : Damn it !
RIPLEY : Wait .
It ´ s OK . It ´ s all right .
Don ´ t be afraid .
See ?
Wait . No , you don ´ t .
It ´ s OK .
You ´ re gonna be all right now .
Shh .
Easy . Easy . It ´ s gonna be OK .
It ´ s all right . You ´ re gonna be OK .
Shh , shh , shh .
Easy . Easy .
GORMAN : What ´ s her name again ?
DIETRICH : Rebecca .
GORMAN : Now think , Rebecca . Concentrate .
Just start at the beginning .
Where are your parents ?
Look , Rebecca , you have to try- -
Gorman , give it a rest , why don ´ t you ?
GORMAN : Total brainlock .
DIETRICH : Physically , she ´ s OK .
Borderline malnutrition , but no permanent damage .
GORMAN : Come on . We ´ re wasting time .
RIPLEY : Try this .
It ´ s a little hot chocolate .
There you go .
Whoop .
That good , huh ?
Uh-oh .
I made a clean spot here .
Now I ´ ve done it .
Guess I ´ ll have to do the whole thing .
Hard to believe there ´ s a little girl under all this .
And a pretty one , too .
You don ´ t talk much , do you ?
HUDSON : Smoking or non-smoking ?
GORMAN : Tell me what you ´ re scanning for .
BURKE : PDTs .
Personal data transmitters .
Every colonist had one surgically implanted .
If they ´ re within twenty klicks , we ´ ll read it out here .
So far , zippo .
I don ´ t know how you stayed alive ...
but you ´ re one brave kid , Rebecca .
Newt .
What ´ d you say ?
My name ´ s Newt .
Nobody calls me Rebecca except my brother .
Newt .
I like that .
I ´ m Ripley .
It ´ s nice to meet you .
And who is this , hmm ?
Casey .
Hello , Casey .
What about your brother ? What ´ s his name ?
Timmy .
RIPLEY : ls Timmy around here , too ?
Maybe hiding like you were ?
Any sisters ?
Mom and Dad ?
Newt , look at me .
Where are they ?
They ´ re dead , all right ? Can I go now ?
I ´ m sorry , Newt .
Don ´ t you think you ´ d be safer here with us ?
These people are here to protect you .
They ´ re soldiers .
It won ´ t make any difference .
SPUNKMEYER : Need anything else ?
Hello , Bishop . Do you need anything else ?
No .
Nice pet you got there .
Magnificent , isn ´ t it ?
Yo ! Stop your grinnin ´ and drop your linen !
Found them .
GORMAN : They alive ?
HUDSON : Unknown , but it looks like all of them ...
over at the processing station ...
sub-level three ...
under the main cooling towers .
HICKS : It looks like a goddamn town meeting .
Let ´ s saddle up , Apone .
APONE : Aye , sir .
Let ´ s go . They ain ´ t paying ´ us by the hour . Head ´ em out .
OK , Frost , you ´ re driving .
It ´ s OK . Don ´ t worry . It ´ ll be OK .
GORMAN : I want a straight " V " deployment ...
second team on left flank .
Advance on axial six-six-four .
Tracker on-line . Set the V-gain to filter R-F ambient .
APONE : Hudson , tracker on-line . Left and right , little buddy .
GORMAN : Forty meters in , bearing two-two-one ...
there should be a stairwell .
APONE : Check . Got it .
GORMAN : You want sub-level three .
APONE : Let ´ s go , people .
Hudson , you got the point .
Hicks , watch our tails .
Nice and easy .
Check those corners .
GORMAN : Watch your spacing .
APONE : You heard the man . Don ´ t bunch up . Stay loose .
GORMAN : Your transmission ´ s showing a lot of break-up .
HUDSON : Probably getting some interference from the structure .
APONE : Use those lights .
GORMAN : Next one down , and proceed on a two-one-six .
APONE : Roger . That ´ s a two-one-six .
GORMAN : I ´ m not making that out too well .
What is it , Hudson ?
HUDSON : You tell me . I only work here .
What is that ?
I don ´ t know .
Proceed inside .
APONE : Watch your fire and check your targets .
Remember , we ´ re looking for civvies in here .
APONE : Easy .
HICKS : Tighten it up , Frost . We ´ re getting a little thin .
APONE : Nice and easy .
DIETRICH : Looks like some sort of secreted resin .
HICKS : Yeah , but secreted from what ?
APONE : Nobody touch nothing .
BURKE : Busy little creatures , huh ?
FROST : Hot as hell in here .
HUDSON : But it ´ s a dry heat .
APONE : Knock it off , Hudson .
Lieutenant , what do those pulse-rifles fire ?
GORMAN : Ten millimeter explosive-tip caseless .
Standard light armor-piercing round . Why ?
RIPLEY : Look where your team is .
They ´ re right under the primary heat exchangers .
So ?
So if they fire their weapons in there ...
won ´ t they rupture the cooling system ?
BURKE : Oh , ho ho . Yeah . She ´ s absolutely right .
So what ?
This whole station is basically a big fusion reactor .
Right ?
So she ´ s talking about a thermonuclear explosion ...
and , " Adiós , muchachos . "
Oh , great . Wonderful .
Shit !
Look .
Uh ... Apone .
We can ´ t have any firing in there .
I want you to collect magazines from everybody .
HUDSON : ls he fuckin ´ crazy ?
FROST : What do we use , harsh language ?
GORMAN : Flame units only . I want rifles slung .
APONE : Sir , l- -
GORMAN : Just do it , Sergeant . And no grenades .
APONE : You heard the man .
Pull ´ em out . Let ´ s have ´ em .
Come on , Vasquez . Clear and lock .
Damn !
You , too . Give it up , Ski .
Crowe , I want it now . Give it up .
DRAKE : Right on , Vas .
APONE : Let ´ s go . Give it up .
Frost , you got the duty . Open that bag .
FROST : Thanks a lot , Sarge .
APONE : Hicks , cover our ass .
Head ´ em out , people .
HICKS : I like to keep this handy for close encounters .
FROST : I heard that .
GORMAN : Any movement ?
HUDSON : Nothing .
Zip .
APONE : Holy shit .
RIPLEY : Newt , go sit up front .
Go on !
Now !
APONE : Steady , people . Let ´ s finish our sweep .
We ´ re still Marines , and we got a job to do .
Keep it moving .
Easy .
- Top ! - What ?
DIETRICH : We got a live one !
You ´ re gonna be all right .
Please ... kill me .
DIETRICH : Stay calm . We ´ ll get you out .
It ´ s gonna be all right .
We ´ ve got to get her out of here .
APONE : What is it , Dietrich ? What ´ s going on ?
Convulsion !
RIPLEY : Ohh !
APONE : Dietrich , get back !
Aah ! Aah !
No !
APONE : Frost , flamethrower !
Get back ! Flamethrower ! Move !
[ Screeching ]
- [ Beeping ] - Movement !
What ´ s the position ?
I can ´ t lock in !
Talk to me , Hudson !
Multiple signals .
They ´ re closing .
APONE : Go to infrared , people . Look sharp !
GORMAN : What ´ s happening , Apone ? We can ´ t see anything in here .
RIPLEY : Pull your team out , Gorman .
HUDSON : I got readings in front and behind .
FROST : Where , man ? I don ´ t see shit .
HICKS : He ´ s right . Nothing ´ s back here .
HUDSON : Something ´ s moving , and it ain ´ t us !
FROST : Oh , shit .
HUDSON : Tracker ´ s off-scale , man .
They ´ re all around us , man ! Jesus !
DIETRICH : Maybe they don ´ t show up on infrared at all .
Aah !
FROST : Aah !
APONE : Frost !
DIETRICH : Aah !
Come on !
CROWE : Aah !
GORMAN : Jesus Christ , Apone ! What is going on ?
HICKS : Wierzbowski and Crowe are down !
APONE : Dietrich , Crowe ! Sound off !
Frost ! Frost !
WIERZBOWSKl : Aah !
Wierzbowski !
VASQUEZ : Let ´ s rock !
DRAKE : Yeah !
Yeah !
Who ´ s firing ? God damn it !
VASQUEZ : Yeah !
I ordered a hold fire .
HUDSON : They ´ re coming out of the goddamn walls ! Let ´ s book !
Uh , Apone ...
I want you to lay down a suppressing fire with ...
APONE : Vasquez , Drake , hold your fire , God damn it !
GORMAN : Are you copying me ?
Lay down a suppressing fire with the incinerators ...
and fall back by squads ...
APONE : Say again ?
All after " incinerator . "
Lay down a suppressing fire with the incinerators ...
and fall back ...
[ Loud gunfire ]
APONE : Aah !
HUDSON : Sarge !
Apone , talk to me .
Apone ? Talk to me !
RIPLEY : He ´ s gone !
[ Shouting and gunfire ]
Get them out of there !
GORMAN : Shut up !
Hicks , whoever ´ s left , get the hell- -
- Shut up ! - God damn it !
HICKS : Where ´ s Apone ? !
Where ´ s Apone ? !
The Sarge is gone ! Let ´ s get the fuck out of here !
HICKS : Let ´ s go , Marines !
Hudson ?
Vasquez ?
HICKS : Hudson , look out !
HUDSON : Get it !
HICKS : Hudson !
GORMAN : Hicks ! Hicks !
HICKS : It ´ s too much ! Fall back !
GORMAN : I told them to fall back .
I told them to fall back .
RIPLEY : They ´ re cut off !
Do something !
Fuck !
HICKS : Keep movin ´ !
RIPLEY : Hold on , Newt .
Ripley , what the hell are you doing ?
GORMAN : Turn around !
That ´ s an order !
RIPLEY : Get off me , damn it !
GORMAN : God damn it , that ´ s an order !
BURKE : You had your chance , Gorman .
HICKS : Come on !
VASQUEZ : Come on , Drake !
DRAKE : Yeah !
HICKS : Let ´ s move it !
VASQUEZ : Come on . Let ´ s go ! Let ´ s go !
HUDSON : It ´ s blocked , man . We got to go around !
RIPLEY : Open the door ! Hicks !
HICKS : Drake , we are leaving !
DRAKE : Run for it !
Shit !
[ Grunting ]
BURKE : Let ´ s go !
VASQUEZ : Drake , come on , man !
Drake , come on !
Aah !
No !
HUDSON : Fire in the hold !
HICKS : He ´ s gone !
VASQUEZ : No ! Drake ´ s out there !
HUDSON : Put it out !
VASQUEZ : Drake ´ s coming !
HICKS : He ´ s gone !
VASQUEZ : No , he ´ s not !
HICKS : Forget him ! He ´ s gone !
Get on the goddamn door !
HICKS : Eat this !
HUDSON : Aah !
HICKS : Ripley ! Go , go , go !
HICKS : Whoa !
GORMAN : Oh .
[ Screeches ]
HICKS : It ´ s all right ! We ´ re clear !
Ripley , you ´ ve blown the transaxle !
You ´ re just grinding metal !
Come on , ease down .
Ease down .
RIPLEY : You OK ?
HUDSON : I ´ m all right .
Get away from me , man !
HICKS : Lieutenant .
RIPLEY : What happened to Gorman ?
HICKS : I don ´ t know ...
maybe a concussion , but he ´ s alive .
VASQUEZ : No , man , he ´ s dead !
Wake up , pendejo ! I ´ m going to kill you !
HICKS : Back off .
Right now .
Somebody get me a first aid kit .
HUDSON : Hey . Hey , look .
The Sarge and Dietrich aren ´ t dead , man .
Their signs are real low , but they ain ´ t dead .
Then we get them .
- We don ´ t leave people behind ! - I ain ´ t going back !
You can ´ t help them !
You can ´ t .
Right now they ´ re being cocooned just like the others .
HUDSON : Oh , dear Lord Jesus , this ain ´ t happening ´ , man .
HICKS : God damn it .
HUDSON : This can ´ t be happenin ´ , man .
This isn ´ t happening ´ !
We ´ ve got seven canisters of CN-20 .
I say we roll them in there and nerve gas the whole nest .
HICKS : It ´ s worth a try , but we don ´ t know if it ´ ll affect them .
HUDSON : Let ´ s bug out and call it even . Why even talk about it ?
RIPLEY : I say we take off and nuke the entire site from orbit .
It ´ s the only way to be sure .
HUDSON : Fuckin ´ " A " !
BURKE : Hold on one second .
This installation has a substantial dollar value .
They can bill me .
OK , look .
This is an emotional moment for all of us , OK ?
I know that .
But let ´ s not make snap judgments , please .
This is clearly an important species we ´ re dealing with ...
and I don ´ t think you or I or anybody has the right ...
to arbitrarily exterminate them .
Wrong .
VASQUEZ : Yeah . Watch us .
HUDSON : Maybe you haven ´ t been keeping up on current events ...
but we just got our asses kicked , pal !
I ´ m not blind to what ´ s going on ...
but I cannot authorize that kind of action . I ´ m sorry .
Well , I believe Corporal Hicks has authority here .
Corporal Hicks is ...
RIPLEY : This operation is under military jurisdiction .
Hicks is next in chain of command , right , Corporal ?
Yeah .
Yeah , that ´ s right .
BURKE : Yeah . Look , Ripley ...
this is a multimillion dollar installation , OK ?
He can ´ t make that decision . He ´ s just a grunt .
Uh , no offense .
HICKS : None taken .
Ferro , do you copy ?
FERRO : Standing by .
HICKS : Prep for dust-off . We need immediate evac .
FERRO : Roger . On our way .
HICKS : I say we take off , nuke the site from orbit .
It ´ s the only way to be sure .
Let ´ s do it .
HICKS : Let ´ s go . Pick it up , Hudson .
Pick it up , baby .
All right . Set him down here .
Move it , Spunkmeyer . We ´ re rolling .
Hold on a second . There ´ s something- -
FERRO : Just get up here .
I ´ m in . Ramp closing .
Spunkmeyer .
God damn it .
[ Door slides open ]
Well , where the fuck- -
Run !
Well , that ´ s great . That ´ s just fuckin ´ great , man .
Now what the fuck are we supposed to do ?
We ´ re in some real pretty shit now , man !
HICKS : Are you finished ?
HICKS : You all right ?
NEWT : I guess we ´ re not gonna be leaving now , right ?
RIPLEY : I ´ m sorry , Newt .
You don ´ t have to be sorry . It wasn ´ t your fault .
HUDSON : That ´ s it , man . Game over , man ! Game over !
What the fuck are we gonna do now ?
What are we gonna do ?
BURKE : Maybe we could build a fire , sing a couple of songs .
Why don ´ t we try that ?
NEWT : We ´ d better get back ´ cause it ´ ll be dark soon ...
and they mostly come at night .
Mostly .
HICKS : That ´ s everything , right ?
This is absolutely everything we could salvage ...
out of the APC wreckage .
We got four pulse-rifles with about fifty rounds each .
That ain ´ t so good .
We got fifteen of these M-40 grenades .
Don ´ t touch that . Dangerous , honey .
RIPLEY : ls that the only flamethrower ?
HICKS : Yeah . It ´ s only half-full , but it ´ s functional .
And another one ´ s damaged .
I don ´ t know about that one .
But the good news ...
we got four of these robot sentries ...
with display and scanners intact .
They really kick ass . They ´ ll come in handy .
How long after we ´ re declared overdue can we expect a rescue ?
Seventeen days .
Seventeen days ?
Hey , man , I don ´ t wanna rain on your parade ...
but we ´ re not gonna last seventeen hours .
Those things are gonna come here like they did before , and- -
Hudson ! Hudson !
This little girl survived longer than that ...
with no weapons and no training .
Right ?
Why don ´ t you put her in charge ?
You better just start dealing with it , Hudson .
Deal with it , because we need you ...
and I ´ m sick of your bullshit .
Now get on a terminal and call up a floor plan file .
Construction blueprints . I don ´ t care .
Anything that shows the layout .
- Are you listening ? - Yeah .
RIPLEY : I need to see air ducts , electrical access tunnels ...
sub-basements ...
every possible way into this complex .
We don ´ t have much time .
OK .
OK , I ´ m on it .
RIPLEY : Hudson !
Just relax .
I ´ ll be in med lab .
I ´ ll check on Gorman , continue my analysis .
Fine .
You do that .
RIPLEY : This service tunnel ...
must be how they ´ re moving back and forth .
HUDSON : That ´ s right .
It moves from the processing station ...
right into the sub-level .
Come down on that .
OK , come over .
Hold it . Go back .
Punch that in there .
HICKS : No . It ´ s back here .
RIPLEY : OK .
There ´ s a pressure door at this end .
Couldn ´ t we put a remote sentry unit in the tunnel ...
then seal that door ?
HICKS : That ´ ll work ...
but we gotta figure on them getting into the complex .
RIPLEY : That ´ s right , so ...
we repair the barricades at these two intersections ...
HICKS : Right .
... and weld plate steel over these ducts here and here ...
and here .
Then they can only come at us from these two corridors .
HICKS : Right . Then we put the other sentry units here ...
and here , right ?
- Right . - Outstanding .
Now all we need is a deck of cards .
Let ´ s move like we ´ ve got a purpose .
HUDSON : Affirmative .
NEWT : Affirmative .
HUDSON : Do your thing , baby .
Come on , Vasquez , let ´ s get out of here .
" A " and " B " sentries are in place and keyed .
HICKS : Roger . Stand by . Arming now .
Test it , Hudson .
- Do it . - Fire in the hole !
HUDSON : Great . Let ´ s get the hell out of here .
We ´ re sealing the tunnel .
Come on , baby .
HICKS : For what it ´ s worth .
I want you to put this on .
RIPLEY : What ´ s it for ?
It ´ s a locator .
Then I can find you anywhere in the complex on this .
It ´ s just a precaution .
Thanks .
Doesn ´ t mean we ´ re engaged or anything .
All right , what ´ s next ?
RIPLEY : Last stop .
Get in .
Scoot down .
That ´ s good .
Now lie here and have a nap .
You ´ re very tired .
I don ´ t want to . I have scary dreams .
Well , I bet Casey doesn ´ t have scary dreams .
Let ´ s take a look .
Nope . Nothing bad in there .
See ?
Maybe you could just try to be like her .
Ripley , she doesn ´ t have bad dreams ...
because she ´ s just a piece of plastic .
Right .
I ´ m sorry , Newt .
RIPLEY : There .
My mommy always said there were no monsters ...
no real ones , but there are .
Yes , there are , aren ´ t there ?
Why do they tell little kids that ?
Most of the time it ´ s true .
Did one of those things grow inside her ?
I don ´ t know , Newt .
That ´ s the truth .
Isn ´ t that how babies come- -
I mean , people babies ?
They grow inside you .
No . That ´ s very different .
NEWT : Did you ever have a baby ?
Yes , I did .
I had a little girl .
Where is she ?
She ´ s gone .
You mean dead .
Here .
Take this .
For luck .
How ´ s that ?
Don ´ t go , please .
Newt , I ´ m gonna be right in the next room .
And you see that camera ?
I can see you through that camera ...
to see if you ´ re safe .
I ´ m not gonna leave you , Newt .
I mean that .
That ´ s a promise .
You promise ?
I cross my heart .
And hope to die ?
And hope to die .
Now go to sleep ...
and don ´ t dream .
Sneak .
BISHOP : The molecular acid oxidizes ...
after the creature ´ s death , completely neutralizing it .
Bishop , that ´ s interesting , but it gets us nowhere .
I ´ m trying to figure out what we ´ re dealing with .
Let ´ s go through it again .
They grab the colonists , they move them over there ...
and they immobilize them to be hosts for more of these .
Which means there would have to be a lot of these parasites .
One for each colonist . That ´ s over a hundred , at least .
Yes . That follows .
Each one of these things comes from an egg , right ?
So who ´ s laying these eggs ?
I ´ m not sure .
It must be something we haven ´ t seen yet .
Hey , maybe it ´ s like an ant hive .
- Bees have hives . - You know what I mean .
There ´ s , like , one female that runs the whole show .
BISHOP : Yes . The queen .
HUDSON : Yeah . The mama .
And she ´ s badass , man . I mean big .
- These things ain ´ t ants . - I know that .
Bishop , I want these specimens destroyed ...
as soon as you ´ re finished with them .
Mr. Burke gave instructions ...
they were to be kept alive for return to the Company labs .
He was very specific about it .
Those two specimens are worth millions ...
to the bio-weapons division .
If you ´ re smart , we can both come out of this heroes ...
and we will be set up for life .
You ´ re crazy , Burke . Do you know that ?
Do you think you can get a dangerous organism ...
past ICC quarantine ?
How can they impound it if they don ´ t know about it ?
But they will know about it , Burke . From me .
Just like they ´ ll know you were responsible ...
for the deaths of one hundred fifty-seven colonists .
BURKE : Wait a second !
- You sent them to that ship . - You ´ re wrong .
I just checked the colony log ...
directive dated 6-12-79 , signed Burke , Carter J.
You sent them out there and didn ´ t even warn them .
Why didn ´ t you warn them , Burke ?
What if that ship didn ´ t even exist ?
Did you think about that ? I didn ´ t know .
So if I made a major security situation out of it ...
everybody steps in ...
and there ´ s no exclusive rights for anybody .
Nobody wins . I made a decision , and it was wrong .
It was a bad call , Ripley .
RIPLEY : Bad call ? These people are dead , Burke !
Haven ´ t you any idea what you ´ ve done ?
I ´ m gonna make sure they nail you right to the wall .
You ´ re not gonna sleaze your way out of this one .
Right to the wall .
Ripley .
You know , I expected more from you .
I thought you ´ d be smarter than this .
I ´ m happy to disappoint you .
[ Alarm from robot sentries ]
HUDSON : What ´ s going on ?
HICKS : They ´ re coming .
- Where ? - In the tunnel .
Here we go .
" A " and " B " gun tracking and firing .
Multiple targets .
[ Aliens screeching over sentry transmitter ]
Look at those ammo counters go .
" B " gun ´ s down 50 percent .
Man , it ´ s a shooting gallery down there .
HICKS : Sixty rounds left on " B. "
Forty ... twenty ... ten .
" B " gun ´ s dry . Twenty on " A. "
Ten ... five ...
That ´ s it .
HUDSON : Jesus . They ´ re wall-to-wall in there .
[ Loud thumping noises ]
They ´ re at the pressure door .
Man , listen to that .
BISHOP : Bishop here . I ´ m afraid I have some bad news .
Well , that ´ s a switch .
RIPLEY : It ´ s very pretty , but what are we looking for ?
BISHOP : That ´ s it . Emergency venting .
HUDSON : That ´ s beautiful , man . That beats it all .
HICKS : How long till it blows ?
BISHOP : Four hours ...
with a blast radius of thirty kilometers ...
equal to about forty megatons .
HICKS : We got problems .
HUDSON : I don ´ t fucking believe this !
HICKS : Vasquez , close the shutters .
RIPLEY : Why can ´ t we shut it down from here ?
BISHOP : The crash caused too much damage .
An overload was inevitable at this point .
HUDSON : Oh , man , I was getting short .
Four more weeks and out .
Now I ´ m going to buy it on this rock .
VASQUEZ : Give us a break !
HUDSON : Four more weeks . Oh , man .
RIPLEY : We need the other drop-ship from the Sulaco .
Can ´ t we bring it down on remote ?
The transmitter was on the APC . It ´ s wasted .
I don ´ t care how . We better think of a way .
HUDSON : Think of what ? We ´ re fucked ! We ´ re doomed !
Shut up ! What about the colony transmitters ?
The uplink tower at the other end ?
The hard-wiring between here and there was damaged .
We can ´ t align the dish .
Somebody ´ s gonna have to go out there ...
take a portable terminal and patch in manually .
Yeah , sure . With those things running around ?
You can count me out .
HICKS : We can count you out of everything .
BISHOP : I ´ ll go .
HUDSON : You go , man .
RIPLEY : What ?
I ´ ll go .
I ´ m the only one qualified to remote-pilot the ship .
HUDSON : Yeah , right , man . Bishop should go .
Good idea .
BISHOP : Believe me , I ´ d prefer not to .
I may be synthetic , but I ´ m not stupid .
RIPLEY : How long ?
BISHOP : This conduit runs almost to the uplink assembly- -
one hundred eighty meters .
Say forty minutes crawling there ...
an hour to patch in and align the antenna ...
thirty minutes to prep the ship ...
and about fifty minutes flight time .
RIPLEY : It ´ s gonna be close .
RIPLEY : Good luck .
BISHOP : See you soon .
Watch your fingers .
Oh .
VASQUEZ : Vaya con Dios , man .
HICKS : This is unbelievable .
Twenty meters and closing . Fifteen .
RIPLEY : How many ?
HICKS : Can ´ t tell . Lots .
" D " gun ´ s down 50 percent .
" C " gun ´ s right behind it .
HUDSON : It ain ´ t stopping ´ em .
Jesus , it ain ´ t stopping ´ em .
HICKS : A hundred and fifty rounds on " D. "
HUDSON : Come on , baby . Come on .
HICKS : One hundred rounds .
HUDSON : Come on , come on .
[ Beeping ]
" D " gun ´ s down to twenty .
Ten .
Damn it !
Wait ! They ´ re retreating .
RIPLEY : The guns stopped them .
You ´ re right .
HICKS : Next time they walk right up and knock .
Yeah , but they don ´ t know that .
They ´ re probably looking for other ways to get in .
That ´ ll take ´ em a while .
- Maybe we got ´ em demoralized . - Shut up .
I want you two walking perimeter .
Move !
HICKS : Hey , listen .
We ´ re all in strung-out shape ...
but stay frosty and alert .
We can ´ t afford to let one of those bastards in here .
All right . Vámonos .
How long ´ s it been since you got any sleep ?
Twenty-four hours ?
Hicks , I ´ m not gonna end up like those others .
You ´ ll take care of it , won ´ t you ?
If it comes to that , I ´ ll do us both .
Let ´ s just make sure it doesn ´ t come to that , all right ?
All right .
Hey , I want to introduce you to a personal friend of mine .
This is an M-41A pulse-rifle , ten millimeter ...
with an over-and-under 30 millimeter grenade launcher .
Feel the weight .
OK , what do I do ?
HICKS : Pull it in tight here .
- Right . - Lean into it .
HICKS : All right , it will kick some .
When the counter reads zero here , you ...
- I press this up ? - That ´ s right .
Get another one in quick . Slap it in hard .
Now you ´ re ready to rock ´ n ´ roll .
- What ´ s this ? - The grenade launcher .
I don ´ t think you want to mess with that .
You started this . Show me everything .
I can handle myself .
Yeah , I noticed .
RIPLEY : How do you feel ?
GORMAN : All right , I guess . One hell of a hangover .
Look , Ripley , I just want- -
RIPLEY : Forget it . Excuse me .
[ Newt moaning ]
RIPLEY : Shh , shh , shh .
It ´ s OK . It ´ s OK .
[ Whispering ] Newt . Wake up .
- What ? - Be quiet .
We ´ re in trouble .
- No ! - Aah !
Move , Newt !
RIPLEY : Hey !
[ No sound ]
NEWT : Help !
Help !
RIPLEY : Hicks !
HICKS : Say again , Bishop ?
You ´ ve got it into auto-refuel mode ...
and it ´ s sequencing right ?
BISHOP : That ´ s right .
HICKS : Good . Stay on it .
Get back to me when you ´ ve activated the launch cycle .
He ´ s at the uplink tower .
BURKE : Terrific .
- Hicks ! Hicks ! - Help ! Help !
Hicks ! Help us !
Break the glass !
Break it , break it .
RIPLEY : I ´ ll try .
Ripley , I ´ m scared .
Me , too .
Stay here .
[ Alarm sounds ]
HICKS : It ´ s the med lab . Hudson !
Vasquez ! Meet me in med lab . We got a fire .
HUDSON : We ´ re on our way .
They ´ re coming , Newt . Oh , please .
Aah !
Uh !
Shoot it out !
- Hudson ! - Jesus !
Oh !
Christ , kid , look out !
Fucking die !
- Over there ! - Yeah !
- Ready ? - Yeah !
HICKS : Hudson !
HUDSON : Yeah , all clear . Nailed the other one .
It ´ s history , man .
HICKS : Jesus .
RIPLEY : Burke . It was Burke .
I say we grease this rat-fuck son of a bitch right now .
HICKS : It just doesn ´ t make any goddamn sense .
RIPLEY : He figured that he could get an alien ...
back through quarantine if one of us was impregnated ...
whatever you call it- -
and then frozen for the trip home .
Nobody would know about the embryos we were carrying ...
me and Newt .
Wait , now . We ´ d all know .
Yes . He could only do it by sabotaging certain freezers ...
on the way home , namely yours .
He could jettison the bodies and make up any story he liked .
HUDSON : Fuck ! He ´ s dead .
You ´ re dog meat , pal .
This is so nuts . Listen to what you ´ re saying .
It ´ s paranoid delusion . It ´ s really sad .
It ´ s pathetic .
Burke , I don ´ t know which species is worse .
They don ´ t fuck each other over for a goddamn percentage .
HICKS : All right , we waste him . No offense .
RIPLEY : No , he ´ s got to go back- -
They cut the power .
HUDSON : What do you mean " they " cut the power ? They ´ re animals .
I want you two with trackers checking the corridors ! Move !
- Gorman , watch Burke . - I got him .
Newt , stay close .
- I ´ ll go this side . - You do that , man .
Anything ?
HUDSON : There ´ s something .
- [ Beeping ] - It ´ s inside the complex .
You ´ re just reading me .
- [ Beeping ] - No , it ain ´ t you .
They ´ re inside the perimeter . They ´ re in here .
RIPLEY : Hudson , stay cool . Vasquez ?
[ Beeps louder ]
Hudson may be right .
RIPLEY : Get back .
HUDSON : The signal ´ s weird .
Must be some interference or something .
There ´ s movement all over the place .
Get back to Operations . It ´ s game time .
Newt .
RIPLEY : Seal the door . Hurry !
HICKS : Come on . Come on , get back .
Work fast .
Cover your eyes , Newt . Don ´ t look at the light .
Movement . Signal ´ s clean . Range , twenty meters .
RIPLEY : They found a way in , something we missed .
HICKS : We didn ´ t miss anything .
HUDSON : Eighteen . Seventeen meters .
RIPLEY : Something under the floor , not in the plans .
- Fifteen meters . - Ripley !
Definitely inside the barricades .
Let ´ s go .
RIPLEY : That ´ s right outside the door . Get back !
HUDSON : This is a big fucking signal .
- How you doing , Vasquez ? - Almost there .
That ´ s it .
HUDSON : Twelve meters .
Eleven . Ten .
- They ´ re right on us . - Nine meters .
Remember- - short , controlled bursts .
Eight meters .
Seven .
Six .
- That ´ s inside the room . - It ´ s reading right !
You ´ re not reading it right .
HUDSON : Five meters , man . Four . What the hell ?
HUDSON : Oh , my God .
HICKS : Give me the light .
Aah !
There they go ! Get them !
- Come on ! - Get them !
BURKE : Do something , Gorman !
HUDSON : Look out ! Look out ! Look out !
There ´ s more of them !
Medical ! Get to medical !
Do it ! Now !
HICKS : Hudson , look out !
Aah !
Now !
Burke !
Open this door ! Burke ! Open it !
Aah !
Come on ! Let ´ s go ! Fall back !
HICKS : Go !
HUDSON : Die , you bastards ! Die , motherfucker !
GORMAN : Burke !
HICKS : Hudson !
Hudson !
HUDSON : Motherfucker !
Come on ! Come on ! Come and get it , baby !
I don ´ t got all day ! Come on , you bastard !
Come on ! You , too ! You want some of this ? Fuck you !
Aah ! Fuck you !
- Hicks ! - Hudson !
[ Hudson screaming ]
VASQUEZ : Come on , Hicks , go !
RIPLEY : It ´ s locked !
HICKS : Got it ! Let ´ s go !
GORMAN : Go ! Go !
- Move , Gorman ! - Seal it !
RIPLEY : Burke ! God damn you ! Open this door !
BURKE : Aah !
HICKS : Get back .
VASQUEZ : Hurry up .
HICKS : Gorman , get out of the way !
NEWT : Ripley , this way .
RIPLEY : Wait . Get behind me .
Whatever you do , do it fast .
- Hicks ! - Come on , let ´ s go .
GORMAN : Move !
- Which way to the landing field ? - This way .
NEWT : Go right .
NEWT : This way .
- Which way ? - Straight ahead and left .
Bishop , do you read me ? Come in . Over .
BISHOP : The ship is on its way . ETA , sixteen minutes .
Stand by there . We ´ re on our way .
- Which way now ? - That way .
- No , wait . This way . - You sure ?
GORMAN : Vasquez , move !
- Right up here . - Hicks !
- We ´ re almost there . - Newt , wait !
Newt !
Yaaa !
Aah !
HICKS : Vasquez !
GORMAN : Go !
Ohh ! Oh , no !
RIPLEY : Newt .
NEWT : Up there , there ´ s a shortcut across the roof .
Hicks .
[ Click click ]
You always were an asshole , Gorman .
RIPLEY : Aah ! Newt !
- Ripley ! - Newt !
Hicks , get her ! Hurry !
Oh ! Hold on , Newt !
- I ´ m slipping ! - Don ´ t let go !
- Ripley ! - Hold on .
- Help ! - Got you .
I got you .
Aah !
Newt ! No !
HICKS : Come on . We can find her with this .
Stay where you are , Newt .
- Ripley ! - We ´ re coming .
Ripley !
[ Beeping ]
This way .
- She ´ s close . - Newt !
Ripley !
RIPLEY : Where are you ? Can you hear me ?
- Newt ! - Here ! I ´ m here !
RIPLEY : Where ?
Newt , are you OK ?
HICKS : Gonna have to cut it .
RIPLEY : Climb down , honey . We ´ ve got to cut through .
Newt ? Now , don ´ t move . Stay very still .
NEWT : OK .
We ´ re almost there . Hang in there , OK ?
[ Beeping ]
Hicks . Hurry .
- I know . - I mean it !
Newt , just stay still .
Aah !
HICKS : Almost there .
RIPLEY : No !
Newt !
No ! No !
- Let ´ s go . - No ! They don ´ t kill you !
They don ´ t kill you ! She ´ s alive ! She ´ s alive !
HICKS : All right , I believe you . She ´ s alive .
We ´ ve got to go . Now !
- Hicks . - Get it off !
Aah ! Get it off ! Aah !
RIPLEY : Here .
[ Hicks groaning ]
RIPLEY : Go .
Come on , you can make it !
RIPLEY : Bishop , how much time ?
BISHOP : Plenty . Twenty-six minutes .
- We ´ re not leaving . - We ´ re not ?
[ Locator beeping ]
BISHOP : Ripley- -
RIPLEY : I don ´ t want to hear about it . She ´ s alive .
BISHOP : ln 19 minutes , this area is gonna be a cloud of vapor ...
the size of Nebraska .
- Don ´ t let him leave . - We ain ´ t going anywhere .
- See you , Hicks . - Dwayne .
It ´ s Dwayne .
Ellen .
Don ´ t be gone long , Ellen .
[ Alarm sounds ]
COMPUTER VOICE : Attention . Emergency .
All personnel must evacuate immediately .
You now have fifteen minutes to reach minimum safe distance .
COMPUTER VOICE : Attention . Emergency .
All personnel must evacuate immediately .
You now have fourteen minutes to reach minimum safe distance .
[ Locator beeping ]
[ Locator beeps faster ]
[ Very fast beeping ]
[ Sobs ]
[ Screaming ]
Aah !
NEWT : Ripley ! Ripley !
RIPLEY : Grab on to me !
Hold on !
[ Hissing ]
[ Screeching ]
NEWT : Let ´ s go !
Behind us !
[ Alarm sounds ]
COMPUTER VOICE : Attention . Emergency .
All personnel must evacuate immediately .
Attention . Emergency .
You now have four minutes to reach minimum safe distance .
[ Queen screeches ]
Come on , God damn it !
Hold on to me !
COMPUTER VOICE : Attention . Emergency .
All personnel must evacuate immediately .
You now have two minutes to reach minimum safe distance .
No .
Bishop , God damn you !
Close your eyes , baby .
NEWT : Look !
NEWT : Come on ! Come on !
Punch it , Bishop !
BISHOP : It ´ s OK . We ´ re OK .
RIPLEY : Hey .
We made it .
NEWT : I knew you ´ d come .
BISHOP : He ´ s gonna be all right .
He ´ s just out . I had to give him another shot for the pain .
We need a stretcher to carry him up to medical .
RIPLEY : OK .
BISHOP : I ´ m sorry if I scared you .
That platform was becoming too unstable .
I had to circle and hope things didn ´ t get too rough ...
to take you off .
RIPLEY : Bishop ... you did OK .
I did ?
Oh , yeah .
Go ! Move !
No ! Here ! Here !
Run !
Here !
Aah !
Get away from her , you bitch !
Come on ! Come on !
Aah !
Ripley !
[ Alarm sounds ]
Aah !
Oh !
[ Screeching ]
Aah !
Bishop !
- Mommy . - Oh , God !
Not bad for a human .
Are we gonna sleep all the way home ?
All the way home .
Can I dream ?
Yes , honey . I think we both can .
- Sleep tight . - Affirmative .